<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Data Engineer Story on Azhar Izzannada Elbachtiar</title><link>https://example.org/tags/data-engineer-story/</link><description>Recent content in Data Engineer Story on Azhar Izzannada Elbachtiar</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.org/tags/data-engineer-story/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AI, DevOps, and the Expanding Role of the Data Engineer</title><link>https://example.org/posts/2024_12_11_ai_devops_and_the_expanding_role_of_the_data_engineer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 07:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/posts/2024_12_11_ai_devops_and_the_expanding_role_of_the_data_engineer/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="blurring-the-lines-data-engineering-meets-devops-software-engineer-and-ml">Blurring the Lines: Data Engineering Meets DevOps, Software Engineer, and ML&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>In data engineering, your work often overlaps with DevOps, software engineering, and machine learning roles. Some companies hire a “full-stack” data engineer who wears all those hats. others split responsibilities into specialized teams. Personally, I love this variety. It’s an opportunity to pick up skills outside the typical data engineering toolkit. Most of these adjacent tasks aren’t as deep or complex as the primary role, but mastering them can position you for broader opportunities. In fact, many data engineers evolve into Solutions Architects at larger organizations by demonstrating cross-functional expertise.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Unwritten Rules of Data Engineering Tools Job Requirements</title><link>https://example.org/posts/2024_09_17_the_unwritten_rules_of_data_engineering_tools_job_requirements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 07:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/posts/2024_09_17_the_unwritten_rules_of_data_engineering_tools_job_requirements/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://example.org/images/A_hu_b8e5f132d2d60c3e.png" alt="A_Post">

&lt;h1 id="the-tool-overload-in-data-engineering">The Tool Overload in Data Engineering&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Data engineering can feel like a never-ending buffet of tools like ETL frameworks, data warehouses, orchestration platforms, container services, and more. Some people even joke that data engineers are really “tool operators”. While each tool can simplify a specific task, juggling too many often makes workflows more complex than consolidating around a handful of versatile solutions. There’s no perfect fit toolset, but identifying the handful of platforms that match your daily workload is key to staying efficient and sane.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spot Instances Cost and Performance Saviour on Short Lived Task</title><link>https://example.org/posts/2024_05_01_spot_instances_cost_and_performance_saviour_on_short_lived_task/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 07:00:00 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/posts/2024_05_01_spot_instances_cost_and_performance_saviour_on_short_lived_task/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="unlocking-the-power-of-spot-instances-for-short-lived-tasks">Unlocking the Power of Spot Instances for Short-Lived Tasks &lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Many people assume Spot Instances are only useful for testing, but they can be a game-changer when applied strategically. If your workload can tolerate interruptions or finishes well within the typical 24-hour eviction window Spot Instances become an incredibly cost-effective option. In my experience, any job that completes in under six hours is a perfect candidate for Spot. You’ll get the exact same performance as a standard on-demand instance, but at a fraction of the cost.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Data Engineer Portfolio Creation Things</title><link>https://example.org/posts/2023_12_31_data_engineer_portfolio_creation_things/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 01:01:01 +0700</pubDate><guid>https://example.org/posts/2023_12_31_data_engineer_portfolio_creation_things/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="learning-by-doing">Learning by Doing&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The principle of learning can take many forms—through different media, structured steps, supportive environments, or any combination that makes the process enjoyable, fun, easy to understand, relaxed, and focused, thereby adding positive value. &lt;strong>Learning by Doing&lt;/strong> is one such approach. Personally, I believe that &lt;strong>mastering the fundamentals&lt;/strong> is essential, but when you’re a programmer or working in a highly technical field, &lt;strong>hands‑on experience&lt;/strong> is crucial for transforming foundational theory into real‑world implementations.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>